Michael Jerred

mjerred.work@gmail.com mjerred.com

Profile

I am an articulate and intelligent programmer, with a strong academic background and four years experience in the web development industry. I have had a real passion for programming since the age of 13, beginning by reverse engineering video games, and have taught myself multiple languages and technologies over the years.

Work Experience

Centaur Media

August 2014 - Feburary 2016

Web Developer

My role at Centaur was to write code for various ASP.NET projects, fixing bugs and developing new features on existing sites; as well as creating brand new sites, as part of a team of 6-7 developers. The sites were built using C# for the back-end, with Microsoft SQL Server for the database engine and Apache Solr for creating indexes. A combination of AngularJs, Bootstrap, Typescript, LESS, jQuery and Knockout were used for the front-end. Mercurial was used for version management.

One of my main achievements was to introduce the AngularJs framework to the team, and use this to create the front-end architecture for two major new projects. These were a great success and the company is now using AngularJs as a standard for future projects.

Example projects:

- The Lawyer Market Intelligence (thelawyermarketintelligence.com) This site was built from the ground up, and including building a custom CMS. At the start I worked alone by designing the structure for the front-end with a combination of AngularJs, LESS and Typescript. After this initial phase the other developers joined in and we each worked on a separate module. Using this approach we were able to develop with a high degree of parallelization, and finished the project in a short space of time.
- Fashion Monitor (fashionmonitor.com) This site had a major design overhaul and all the code was built from scratch, using a previously existing database. I used roughly the same architecture for the front-end as I used in the Lawyer Market Intelligence project, and we again developed it in a highly modular fashion with many developers working in parallel.
- Celebrity Intelligence (celebrityintelligence.com) My main involvement with this site was the creation of a search widget on the home page. It is able to filter by many different categories and display a count of the results very quickly, so to do this fast enough required using Apache Solr to create indexes from complex SQL queries.

Acturis

August 2012 – June 2014

Junior Web Developer

My role at Acturis was to maintain and add features to the company's product as part of an Agile development team. The product was mostly written in C#, SQL, HTML, CSS and Javascript with jQuery; there was also a lot of work with XML configuration files. The C# code was unit tested using Moq, and Subversion (SVN) was used for version management.

Example projects include many business to business and some business to client insurance sites (see www.acturis.com/our-clients).

Technologies

Excellent C#, LINQ, ASP.NET 4, AngularJs, Typescript, LESS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, Git,

Mecurial, Windows

Competent Node.js, Gulp, SQL, MongoDB, ASP.NET Core, Apache Solr, Google Cloud Platform, x86 ASM,

C++, Linux

Learning Angular2, Haskell, Machine Learning

Education

2008 - 2012 MSci. Mathematics and Physics

2:1

University of Bristol

2008 UK Physics Olympiad

Gold medal & one of 15 chosen to attend the International Olympiad preparation camp University of Oxford

2008 Physics Advanced Extension Award

Merit

The Manchester Grammar School

2006 - 2008 5x A2 Level (AAAAB)

Physics, Chemistry, Maths, Further Maths, Further Maths Additional *The Manchester Grammar School*

2001 - 2006 10x GCSE

The Manchester Grammar School

References available upon request.